HITESH NATHURAM DIVEKAR

Kandivali (E) mumbai-400101 • hiteshdivekar33@gmail.com • 8286619375 GitHub link: <u>GitHub account</u> | Portfolio Link: <u>Portfolio</u> | LinkedIn Link : <u>LinkedIn</u>

Profile

- Python developer with 6+ years of experience.
- Experience in developing and designing web application in python, Django, flask.
- Experience of working in an agile environment (Scrum)
- Development experience in the NBFC and fin-tech trading domains.

Skills

Programming & scripting Web Framework

Python, JavaScript, PHP, Bash Django, Flask, web2py, Fast-API, jQuery

Database Frontend Technologies

MySQL, MongoDB, Apache Cassandra HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Repository & Tracker Deployment & DevOps

Git, Click Up, GitLab, Bitbucket AWS EC2, Gunicorn(WSGI server), Nginx(reverse proxy)

Libraries and tools

Data Analysis

pandas, NumPy, Scrappy, Matplotlib,

BeautifulSoup, TA-Lib, Pandas-ta, Yfinance

Database Libraries

PyMongo, MySQL-connector-python,

Cassandra-driver

DB Tools IDE / Editor

MySQL Workbench, DBeaver, DataGrip Sublime Text, PyCharm, Atom, VS Code

Professional Experience		
Aug 2021 – present	Software Engineer, ALKALYME SOLUTIONS LLP Design and developed scripts and web application.	Mumbai, India
Nov 2020 – Jul 2021	Python Developer, DFLTech (Dhanvarsha Finanace Ltd.) ☑ Design and development of API and web application.	Mumbai, India
May 2018 – Sep 2020	Jr. Python Developer, Track-point GPS Pvt. Ltd. Development and design of web application	Mumbai, India

Education		
2018	B.Sc. IT, Sathaye college/Mumbai University	Mumbai, India
2015	H.S.C, Mahatma Phule Arts Science & Commerce	Mumbai, India
2013	S.S.C, Samata Vidaya Mandir	Mumbai, India

Projects

Algo Trading system

- . Real-Time Analysis: Analyze live data to detect buy and sell signals based on predefined conditions.
- . Decision Support: Provide insights and signals to help users make informed trading decisions.
- . Algorithmic Trading: Implement algorithmic trading strategies for both equity and options markets, automating the trading process using python and PHP.

Alternate Data Engine

This project is a kind of artificial intelligence which helps company to approve or reject short term loan in few minutes. On basis of customer's messages which retrieve from android phone using python API.

Real Estate eCommerce Platform

Developed a Django-based platform for real estate brokerage, facilitating property transactions, rentals (including paying guest accommodations for boys and girls), plots, shops, resale, and underconstruction properties. Acts as a mediator connecting buyers and sellers, with a responsive front-end using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Duties and Responsibilities

- . Write reusable, testable, and efficient code
- . Design and implement of low-latency, high-availability, and performative applications
- . Integration of user-facing elements developed by front-end developers with server-side logic
- . Implementation of security and data protection
- . Integration of data storage solutions
- . Performance tuning, improvement, balancing, usability, automation
- . Work collaboratively with design team to understand end user requirements to provide technical solutions and for the implementation of new software features